Labor Editorial Files 5693
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  July-August; Correspondence from H.S. Jeffrey to Keating re_ the attempt to raise more money for the suit; from White and Moore to Keating re_ once again that libel suit, will submit entire matter to Chairman of FTC and wait for voluntary judgment; from Keating to Thompson (FTC) in attempt to secure voluntary decision re Labor's printing of the allegedly libelous material; commendatory letter from Rear Admiral C.P. Plunkett to Lt. Col. William Harllee; from Keating to Keep complaining about Morris Hillquit power grabs; also letter from Keep to Keating re_ the Clayton Act and court decisions in the Colorado & Pennsylvania Mining cases; also correspondence re how Debs beat it out of West Virginia before he was arrested; from Venable to Keating re_ the deportation from towns of Labor members by local police; correspondence from Thompson to Keating in re Keating's request for voluntary decision in Mack-Miller Candle Corp.; circular from the IAM (#l6l) re Special Labor Day edition of Labor showing why Lafollette and Wheeler should be elected; telegram and correspondence re signing an endorsement sheet for Lafollette; from Keep to Keating re_ the Kansas City meeting.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  Sept.-Oct.; Handwritten correspondence to Keating from Keep re prediction of forthcoming events in Austria and Italy; curriculum outline on party organization by Phillips Bradley sent to Keating for possible publication in Labor; Sept. 1919 issue of Catholics & Prohibition with attached correspondence from Father George Zunchen; from Spencer Miller Jr., Secretary of the Workers Education Bureau to Keating with enclosure of Prof. Bradley's outline of the "party system"; from Ethel M. Smith, Leg-Sec. National Women's Trade Union League to Keating re establishing a fighting front on the Child Labor Amendment.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  Nov.-Dec; From Ethel M. Smith to Keating re Child Labor Amendment and also enclosed the churches position against the union in, "The Shame of Massachusetts;" copy of the Pilot, official organ of the Archdiocese of Boston, re William Cardinal O'Connell's (Archbishop of Boston) antagonism toward the Child Labor Amendment; also enclosed an undated list of Massachusetts Mills owning southern plants; From Thomas M. Pierson, 2nd VP, ORT, to Keating re the loss in the "Casey for Congress Campaign;" From Carl Vrooman, Bd. of Dir. of the Farmers Political Conference (ill.) to Keating re the formation of their organization which hopes to become the biggest political farm organization in America, contains enclosure, "Declaration of Principles of the Organization" and misc.; Correspondence from M.W. Martin, Editor of Journal of the International Brotherhood of Blacksmiths, Drop Forgers and Helpers to Keating re_ a new Labor subscription drive; from Keating to Keep re the loss of Lafollette in the election and the great damage to the progressive movement - Keating blames Morris Hillquit; from Keep to Keating re_ same -also evidence that electoral ballots in some states were miscounted; telegram from Palmer (?) to Keating re the final election figures not yet published; from MacGowan to Keating re the "Chicago Transaction Situation."
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  Partial report undated, apparently re Lafollette campaign; from Venable to Keating re_ a certain manager problem on the M&NA Railroad; from Keating to Phil Ziegler explaining, how Labor began; from William Lemke to E.C. Davidson requesting Davidson's endorsement for Lemke as Ambassador to Mexico and then Davidson's request to Keating for advice.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  Feb.-Aug.; Correspondence from Spencer Miller Jr., Secretary of the Workers Education Bureau to Keating re a proposition to write a history of the railroad labor organizations, funded by Labor; Summary of the Minutes of the 5th Annual Conference of Editor's, official railroad magazine; Memo to Mr. Wills from Keating re_ Riddick Lockwood affair and corrupt politicians; from Keating to James Mellvena, Chief Engineer Div. 308, BLE re Canadian Editor of Labor; audit report of the Labor Cooperative Educational and Publishing Society, Inc., 192^-25; More correspondence from Spencer Miller to Keating re_ the history of the railroad labor organization in America, contains tentative outline for a 12 chapter book, further enclosed is a breakdown of expenditures; memo to Keating listing total operating expenses and revenue of Labor; from McAdoo to Keating re McAdoo rejects idea of running for the senate; from E. Kruse, VP of the Mid-West Brotherhood of Locomotive Engineers Securities Corp. to Keating serving as a report on alleged Communist, Otto S. Wangerin.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Sept.-Dec. 8th; Labor Cooperative Educational and Publishing Society, Treasurer's Report; from Keating to Emil Jergensen, Manufacturers & Merchant Federal Tax League re publication of articles about one, Professor Ely; correspondence re_ dinner Labor is holding in honor of Robert Lafollette Jr.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  Dec. 10th-24th; Correspondence re Lafollette dinner; press release entitled, "Complimentary Dinner to Senator Robert M. Lafollette of Wisconsin, Tues., Dec. 15, 1925," release also includes transcript of Lafollette's speech and newspaper clippings.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  Presumably a banquet attendance list for Lafollette dinner.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  January-June; Correspondence from Albert F. Coyle to Keating re Matthew Woll and his reactionary and "misguided attack against friends of labor;" correspondence and enclosed article on "Government Telephones in Manitoba" from J.A.P. Haydon, Canadian Labor to Keating; from John J. Casey, Business Agent, Local 147 of Plumbers and Steam Fitters to Keating re request for information against the Wilkes- Barre Chamber of Commerce; from William A. Cullop, candidate for Democratic nomination in U.S. Senate to Keating asking Keating for a political endorsement; from George F. Milton to Keating re Tennessee Executive Committee vote to abolish 2/3's rule; copy of resolution no. 33 by labor delegates of the Pennsylvania labor movement re establishment of a Pennsylvania edition of Labor; from L.E. Keller, Statistician, Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees to Keating re_ enclosed table and comments in purchasing power of wages of M&WE
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  July 6th-17th; Correspondence from A. Johnston, Grand Chief Engineer, BLE to Keating re_ decision rendered by Indiana Court upholding the laws of the BLE; from A.A. Graham, Attorney to William Green re_ anti church remarks about their anti-labor, pro-slavery attitude; between Keating and Emil Jorgensen and Senator C.C. Cook re_ the case of Professor Ely, also enclosed one copy of "The Case of Professor Richard T. Ely," by Jorgensen, pub. by the Manufacturer and Merchants Federal Tax League; correspondence from J.A.P. Haydon, VP, Ontario & Quebec Conference of Typographical Unions to Keating re Prime Minister of Canada, Arthur Meighen; Handwritten correspondence from J.S. Brown to Keating re pension differentials on the Pennsylvania and Pittsburgh Railway and possible investigation thereto; pamphlet re_ the Second Annual Railroad Labor Institute at Brookwood Labor School.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  July 18th-26th; Correspondence from A. Graham to William Green re_ Green's "stabbing labor in the back in his speech against the general strike in Denver;" from Calif. State Senator Charles Lewis to Keating re_ the ravages of false ice cream; Correspondence from Keep to Keating re American Ambassador to Germany's speech "which was a plea for dictatorship"; from Keep to Keating re_ attempts of women to secure employment on the railroads; article, "Reminiscences on the Metamorphosis of the Labor Movement," by Louis Ludlow, with attached correspondence; newspaper clippings with attached letter from Keating to C.S. Adams on municipal ownership of electric plants; anonymous mss. entitled, "British Government Denies Wireless for Shaw," re how the government denied G.B. Shaw access to a wireless during speech in London.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  July 27th-31st; Correspondence from May F. Lathrop to Keating re the meeting of the Commission on Uniform Laws, Lathrop being the former Chairman of the Committee on Laws Concerning Women and Children; from William Green to Keating re American Bar Association meeting in Denver; from Norman Lombard, Executive Dir. of the Stable Money Association giving Keating membership in that Organization, also enclosed pamphlet "The Evil Consequences of our Unstable Dollar," by Lombard; Correspondence from Keep to Keating re_ "that dirty skunk" Hawes; from Florence Kelly, General Secretary National Consumers' League re workmen's compensation for children; handwritten notes of Fred Barr, BLF&E re the Western Maryland Railroad strike.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Aug. 1st-10th; Newspaper clipping re Colorado's Statehood, correspondence included from Louis Cunningham, Gazette & Tele. Co. gives Keating's pen name as Elliot Harris; from A.A. Graham to William Green, again blasting Green; from John P. Burke, Pres. IBPS&PMW re attempts to organize the paper workers in Quebec; from H.S. Jeffrey to A.N. Haig re_ Jeffrey's prophetic prediction of the downfall of labor leader J.A. Franklin, B.M. Jewell, and W.H. Johnston, also enclosed is flyer for Jeffrey's new book, Man's Inhumanity to Man; press telegram to Keating from A. Johnston re annual union meeting of the BLE in Winnipeg; from Fred Barr to W.S. Hotchkiss re the death of an alleged scab named Hammond; from Charles Lewis, Calif. State Senator to Keating re_ canals as transportation in U.S.; from A.A. Graham to William Green re_ Green's opposition of the labor government in Mexico; between Fred Barr and Keating (correspondence & clippings) re events of the railroad strike in Thomas, West Virginia; clipping from San Jose Calif., entitled "American Labor and Russia;" from Keating to M.J. Helalien re Mexico's President's religious tirade against Catholics.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  Aug. 11th-25th; Mss. by Keating re the labor press; from Keating to C.A. Harley re possible fraud of the mail order houses; handwritten letter and article entitled "Real Wages" by Charles P. Kraft; from Benjamin Judkins re that land sale and water rights scheme in San Diego (includes clippings); from Keating to George L. Eppler re the voting record of Senator Zihlman; from Fred Barr to Keating re a train wreck in West Maryland; from Charles Chaison, Chairman, Mich. Leg. Bd., BLE, to Keating re attempt to prevent re-election of Cong. Frank D. Scott; reprint of the "Pennsylvania Dutch Farmer Plan," from the Gettysburg Compiler; from Fred Barr to Keating re events during the Western and Maryland Railroad strike
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  Aug. 26th-31st; Misc. clippings on the seniority war on the Grand Trunk Railroad; from Keating to Ben Hillard re Congressman Vaile's voting record, particularly in reference to oil magnate; from Ralph M. Easly to Keating re flaws in the primary system; from Keep to Keating re access to political records; additional correspondence between Keating and Easly re getting people to the polls, etc.; From Keating to W.L. Hamilton, Pres. BBDEA re President Harding's role in 1922 shop craft strike; from Thomas Duncan, Madison, Wisconsin, Assembly Chairman, re_ the Lenroot use of Edward Melms endorsement to secure labor votes, (enclosed letter from Melms indicating that Melms did not endorse Sen. Lenroot).
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  Sept. 1st-16th; Handwritten correspondence from Samuel Glatfelter, Congressman, Pennsylvania re candidate endorsement; from Charles H. Lewis, California State Senate to Keating re the regulation of the public utilities; article from A. Blankenhorn to Keating entitled, "AFL Delegate Farrington Not Going to Tennessee Valley Commission," also enclosed correspondence explaining story re sell-out of contracts of the miners
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Sept. 18th-30th; Clippings and correspondence from Keating re American antagonism toward England and the U.N.; from Keating to William C. Harllee re politics (evidently not the first between them) specifically re the progressive movement; from Judson King to Keating re Governor Sweet as candidate for Senator; from Carlson, Intl. Pres. of Switchmen's Union to Keating re Arkansas special edition of Labor; from Henry Hunt, Lawyer, to Keating requesting aid for Passaic NJ strikers; from P.H. Callahan to Denis McCarthy and Newton Baker re_ Governor Smith and the religious issue.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Oct. 1st-10th; Several newspaper clippings sent to Keating re klanism in Arkansas; correspondence from P.M. Abbott to Keating with article entitled, "California's Political Parties State Platforms;" from Ben Deacon, U.S. Press Representative, Canadian National Railways, to Keating re mineral deposits in Canada; from William Holly, Chairman Finance Committee of Public Ownership League to Judson King re_ public ownership at Mussel Shoals Power Co.; "special correspondence," re the trial of Henry M. Daugherty for conspiracy to defraud the U.S. Government; Correspondence from a group who after spending a month in Russia declare the U.S. Government should recognize Russia (enclosed a photo of an American admiring the Russian Crown Jewels); from Homer Bane, Counsel, Tacoma, to Keating re public ownership of water power in Tacoma; from JAP Hayden to Keating re Hayden's investigation of the overworking of Canadian prison guards; article by Judson King with enclosure to Keating re the I & R investigation of public ownership of waterworks; article from Herald Examiner (Chicago) entitled, "Russian Ruler (Stalin) Wants U.S. As Friend."
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Oct. 12th-23rd; Reprint of National Association of Manufacturers, "Cutting Down Immigration Has Ended the Day of Cheap Labor," sent by H. Hull, Comm. General of Immigration; correspondence from Florence Kelly, National Consumers League re_ the possible literary abuses of Labor in citing the League; Telegram from William P. Henry to Keating announcing the death of Eugene V. Debs; from J.T. Brownie, President Amalgamated Engineering Union re unification of the metal workers; from Benjamin Judkins to Keating re the same San Diego land scandal; from Keep re Labor's position on Congressman Lyle; from F.H. Knight, Asst. General President BRAC re the Texas open port law being declared unconstitutional.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Oct. 28th-30th; From David E. Lilienthal to Keating re the Child Labor Law; from Keating to J.E. Hewell re_ the Child Labor Amendment; from Keating to C.E. Baxter re Labor's endorsement policy for political candidates; from JAP Hayden to Keating re inquiring into the Canadian Hydro Power issue; from Hubert Herrins, Director, The Seminar on Relations with Mexico requesting Keating's presence at seminar; from Keating to Max Akridge re_ the situation in Mexico and why the Calles regime was supportive; from W.J. Adms, Editor and Manager, Railway Carmen's Journal re translation of Labor into French for the Quebec Province and the Hydro issue.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  Nov. 1st-9th; Newspaper clippings sent to Keating re_ the role of the church as progressive or reactionary; flyer on the motion picture "The Passaic Textile Strike - The First Motion Picture ever to be Made About Workers on Strike;" correspondence between P.H Callahan and Thomas Lawler, also with Dan Bride re William Jennings Bryan and prohibition; between Dowling and Keating re AFL Insurance Co.; from H.P. Fagan to Keating re the election changes of Smith Brookhart in the Iowa primaries; report from J.M. Clarke re the convention of papermakers in NY; form letter signed by William M. Schultz Jr., Gen. Manager of the Union Mutual Casualty Co., to "All Railroad Men" re new non-cancellable income policy.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  Nov. 10th-13th; Correspondence from John E. Hill, Southern Colorado Bank to Keating re William Sweet's senatorial race loss, attributing the loss to the farm vote; telegram from Keating to Durham County Press re overproduction in the coal mines; from Keating to Hubert Blankenhorn re the election results and how labor stood up; from J.W. Bryan, one time "Bull Moose" Congressman from Washington to Keating re his "ABC" movement pamphlet; from A.A. Graham to Green re how undemocratic the AFL is.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  Nov. 16th-20th; Correspondence from W.R. Jackson to Keating re municipal light plants; from Norman Hapgood, Chairman Wheeler Defense Committee, to Keating enclosing last resolution adopted by that body; handwritten correspondence from JAP Hayden to Keating re change of policy on the Hydro-Electric Power Commission of Ontario; from Keating to Albert Coyle, Editor, BLE Journal re Pennsylvania wage increase for shopmen; clippings sent to Keating by P.H. Callahan re_ prohibition and "The Social Question in Mexico."
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  Nov. 22nd-30th; Correspondence from Luther D. Armstrong of "The New Store" to Keating re labor's policy of US intervention into the Philippines; from P.H. Callahan to Joseph Torello and David Walsh re Catholics in politics; from Marguerite Owners to Keating re Nevada's election of a Republican governor; from Jesse T. Kennedy to Keating re the Migratory Workers Union; release by the BLF&E "Sweeping Victory for Candidates Endorsed by Labor in Carbon County, Pa."; from Keep to Keating re Mussolini; newspaper clipping sent by Clinton Johnson to Keating re land frauds; press release by William A. Wolff re_ the trial of Edward L. Doheny and Albert E. Fall; from Keating to William Atkinson, Ass. Pres, Boilermakers, re the voting record of Atlee Pomerene, former Ohio Senator; article from Henry Flury on "The Dew of Death" - poison gas; from Keep to Keating ,con't) re_ the Farm Bureau Federation and progressives, includes clipping on Nagel Committee.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Dec. 1st-8th; Correspondence from Keating to T.W. Donnelly, Arizona State Senate, re the labor position of Governor Hunt; from Mrs. Walter Gum, Pres. L. 531 BLF&E to Keating re article on new women's auxiliary from Arkansas; from JAP Hayden to Keating re the Canadian railroad conductor strike; from Mercer Green to Keating re company unionism; from Jesse T. Kennedy to Keating migratory workers; from Vaughn Backman to Keating re pamphlets on court amendment to abolish war published by the Women's Peace Union; pamphlet from the Second Conference on the Cause and Cure of War; from J.B. Carwell to Keating re_ the religious situation in Mexico; from Keating to E.H. Fitzgerald, Grand President, Brotherhood. of Railway Clerks re_ recent Supreme Court decision involving ICC; circular entitled, "Synopsis of Sugar Situation and the Development of Long Island to Sugar Beet Culture," by Kurt Grunwald, and correspondence re_ the potential of sugar beets on a railroad crop; Program for the 20th Annual Meeting of the American Association for Labor Legislation.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Dec. 12th-18th; Correspondence from JAP Hayden to Keating re the strike of the BRC on the Canadian Pacific Railroad; from Blank to Keating re_ French censorship of American press; obituary of Albert Eugene King, Gen. Secretary Treasurer of the BRT; article sent by Keep to Keating entitled, "Italy Puts Yoke on Capital and Labor" also correspondence on Italy Leaders Maletesta and Mussolini; from Hayden to Keating re_ the CNR Railroad of the Carmen and wages of Canadian Railroad workers; from Carl Berg, Swamp field Farm to Keating re tax refund Mellon-Coolidge proposal.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Dec. 19th-31st; Correspondence from Florence Kelley, Gen. Sec., National Consumers League re children's compensation for industrial injuries; article by JAP Hayden to Keating re_ the Canadian-American railroad freight differential.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  Correspondence from Jesse Kennedy to Keating re migratory workers with enclosed article entitled "The Migratory Workers" by George W. Campbell; statement by Brookhart, apparently before a Conference of the Corn and Cotton Belt, also contains the remarks of Abe D. Waldaves; mss. entitled "Wild Scenes as France Revises Its Constitution to Save France"; article, "British Labor's Daily Gets New Editor and Goes Out to Fight"; other mss. entitled, "British Labor Down and Going Lower," "Big China Giant Gives Another Shake," "Bromley and Hicks Sailing for USA, Will Tell British Railwaymen Stand," "Labor Party Talks and Waits, There's Nothing Else To Do," European Metalworkers-Found Much to Praise and Some to Blame in USA," "British Union Still Reducing Benefit," "Why Mussolini Continues to Be Most Hated Ruler," "Putting the Last Screws On the Miners"; article, "Wage Increase to Canadian Rail Workers Justified," also, "Canada's Deputy Minister of Labor"; copy of statement made by Albert Coyle, Editor of BLE Journal in reply to "attack" by John Lewis at AFL Detroit convention.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Jan. 3rd-10th; Correspondence from Norman Thomas, Executive Director, League for Industrial Democracy, re_ organization of the Pullman Porters; from Keating to Martin F. Ryan, Gen. President, BRC, re the credentials of JAP Hayden; from D.B. Robertson, President, BLF&E re Brandeis' attempt to set up railroad library at University of Louisville.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Jan. 11th-25th; Correspondence from Wallace M. Short to Keating re the Missouri River project, also, newspaper clippings; from Robertson re negotiations of the BLF&E; pamphlet, National Bureau of Information and Education re distribution of wealth; from Robertson re troubles on the Canadian National Railway.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  Jan. 26th-31st; Correspondence from W.S. Warfield, President of Order of Sleeping Car Conductors re_ scalping of railroad tickets by employees; from A. Philip Randolph, General Organizer, Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters re history of the organization and organizational activities; from B.J. Whitley to Keating re Mexican immigration and effect on labor movement.
- Correspondence of Edward Keating, Editor, Labor, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 8)